ctan.org 2019-12-31

# CTAN: CTAN Privacy Policy

Version 2018-03-01

## Scope

This privacy statement covers the direct access of users to the content of the Comprehensive TeX Archive Network (CTAN) via it's primary server. Especially the access via the Web site is covered herin.

We take care to protect the privacy of our users and contributors. This statement describes our measures and the impact on you as our user.

## Collecting and using data

We collect data to fulfill our services to the public community. This includes

  * the upload of packages,
  * the communication with the CTAN Team via upload form or email,
  * the guest book entries,
  * the registered users,
  * the rating and commenting of packages and users.

Data you pass to CTAN for the purpose to be publicly presented are &ellip; public. This contains all information included in uploaded packages and any other contribution.

You have the choice that your email address and other private data is not made available publicly. This is the default. Thus you have to explicitly agree before we pass on your data (opt-in).

Nevertheless we have to know who is using our services – at least to protect ourself in case of illegal content. Thus you have to identify yourself at least internally to the CTAN Team. It is your free decision. If you don't want this then simply stay away from CTAN upload or user registration.

## Sharing of your information

We will not rent or sell your information to third parties.

## Integration of third-party services

The CTAN Web site uses the Google GeoMap service to display a map on the mirrors page. This leads to a direct request to retrieve the necessary page fragments. Thus Google may collect data about your visits of this page. 

## Social community links

The CTAN Web site contains links to the community sites [Twitter](https://twitter.com/) (white pigeon on blue background), [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/) (white f on blue background), [Google+](https://plus.google.com/) (white g+ on red background), [LinkedIn](http://www.linkedin.com//) (white in on blue background), [Pinterest](http://pinterest.com/) (white P on red background), [Xing](https://www.xing.com//) (white X on dark green background), [Reddit](http://www.reddit.com/) (reddit alien on white background), [Tumblr](http://www.tumblr.com/) (white t on blue background), [StumbleUpon](http://www.stumbleupon.com/) (white su on red background). No data is transmitted to one of those sites unless you click on one of the links. 

## Cookies

The CTAN site uses cookies to store information about the settings of a user on his computer. This information is not used nor can it be used to gain further insight in the personal data of the user.

The CTAN site can be used with cookies disabled. This leads to a minor restriction of the adaptability of the site to the user's taste. Most functionality remains intact.

## Registration

The data collected during registration are kept for the purpose to fulfill the CTAN services. Your data is only made public if you enable this during the registration process or on the personal configuration page afterwards.

A registered user can request the deletion of his account. In this case all data is deleted and can not be restored for whatever purpose.

## Rating and Voting

The CTAN site may allow a registered user to participate in ratings and votings. In this case the decisions of the user are stored together with the association to the user account.

## Access Recording and Server Log Files

We record the access to our services in server log files. They contain the information about date and time of access and the request received. We keep this data for the purpose to improve our services. We do not try to track down individual users. We do not pass on this information to anybody outside the CTAN team. The log files are only kept temporarily.

## No Abuse

CTAN reserves the right to delete any contribution which is illegal or not appropriate on CTAN without any notice.

## Changes of the Privacy Statement

The CTAN Team reserves the right to change the privacy statement. The privacy statement is published in it's current form on the Web site of CTAN.

## Information, Corrections and Deletion

Any user can request the data stored for him. For this purpose write to [ctan@ctan.org](mailto:ctan@ctan.org). 

The same address can be used to request corrections or deletion of data for a user.

## No Warranty

The services of CTAN are offered to the public free of obligations of any kind. We can not guarantee that the services are available at any time or functioning at all.

We can not guarantee that the packages provided for download are free of errors or malicious code or that they are functioning at all to solve any specific task.

We can not guarantee that the packages provided for download are free of third-party rights. We provide the information about the licenses without any warranty. Before using the packages you should take care to follow the restrictions of the respective licenses.

We can not guarantee that links in the context of packages may not lead you to pages of legally questionable or malicious content. Beware of any external links.

## Instances where we are required to share your information

CTAN will disclose your information where required to do so by law or subpoena or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to

  1. comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement;
  2. to enforce our Terms of Use or to protect the security, quality or integrity of our Service; and/or
  3. to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of CTAN, our Users, or others.

## How we store and protect your information

Your information collected through the Service may be stored and processed in Germany or any other country in which CTAN or its service providers maintain facilities

## Your choices about your information

You control your account information and settings: You may update your account information and email-communication preferences at any time by logging in to your account and changing your profile settings at <https://www.ctan.org/settings>. 

## Opting out of collection of your information for tracking

Please refer to your mobile device or browser’s technical information for instructions on how to delete and disable cookies, and other tracking/recording tools. Depending on your type of device, it may not be possible to delete or disable tracking mechanisms on your mobile device. Note that disabling cookies and/or other tracking tools prevents CTAN from tracking your browser’s activities in relation to the Service. However, doing so may disable some of the features available through the Service. 

## Links to other web sites and services

We are not responsible for the practices employed by web sites or services linked to or from the Service, including the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another web site, our Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party web sites or services. Your browsing and interaction on any third-party web site or service, including those that have a link or advertisement on our web site, are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies. 

In addition, you agree that we are not responsible and we do not control over any third-parties that you authorize to access your User Content. If you are using a third-party web site or service (like Facebook, Google groups, or an IRC chat room) and you allow such a third-party access to your User Content you do so at your own risk. 

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources other than through the Service.
